(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T13:34:52.364221",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Yeah!!
どこへ行こうか 計画ナシで
Where should we go, with no plan?
歌いながら気の向く方へ
Singing as we follow our whims.
迷ってるの？ 冒険してるの？
Are we lost? Are we on an adventure?
それはみんな次第！
That's entirely up to everyone!
まだまだ楽しみ足りない
There's still not enough fun,
でもでも時間が足りない
but, but we don't have enough time!
ワクワクする明日へ
Toward an exciting tomorrow,
思い切って 張り切って 前向いて
taking the plunge, going all out, looking ahead,
さあ、進もう！
let's move forward!
せーのっ！
Ready, go!
いつだって本気で！
Always going all out!
遊び尽くしちゃえ！
Let's play to our hearts' content!
やりすぎちゃうくらいで
To the point of going overboard,
イッツ・オーライ！
it's all right!
早起きよりも 徹夜しちゃおう
Instead of waking up early, let's pull an all-nighter!
なんとかなっちゃうはずだから！
Because it'll somehow work out!
ピンチはチャンスになるからさ
Pinches turn into chances,
イッツ・オール・オッケー！
it's all okay!
みんなで笑えば無敵だね
If we laugh together, we're invincible!
なんだって全力で！
No matter what, with all our might!
突き抜けちゃって！
Break right through!
真っ直ぐな気持ちで行こう！
Let's go with straight, honest feelings!
ホップステップジャンプで飛び出そう！
Let's leap out with a hop, step, and jump!
Yeah!!
順調に行くだけじゃ
Just going smoothly
それはそれで退屈だね
is pretty boring in itself.
わがままかも しれないけど
It might be selfish, but
失敗は成功の元！
failure is the stepping stone to success!
とかカッコつけてみたけど やらかしちゃった日の夜は
Trying to look cool, but on nights when I messed up,
枕に向かって叫んだ
I shouted into my pillow.
それもみんなが聞いてくれるから 悪くないよね！
But everyone listens to me, so that's not bad at all!
せーのっ！
Ready, go!
今しかできない！
Things we can only do now,
ことをしようよ
let's do them!
心配ご無用はママ…？
No worries whatsoever...
走る前から
Before we even start running,
つまずくことを
worrying about stumbling
考えてちゃしょうがない
gets us nowhere.
もしも雨が降ったとしたら
If it happens to rain,
とっておきの傘をさそうよ
let's open our special umbrella.
なんだって全力で突き抜けちゃって！
With all our might, let's break through!
真っ直ぐな気持ちで行こう！
Let's go with straight, honest feelings!
ホップステップジャンプで飛び出そう！
Hop, step, and jump, let's leap out!
なかなかお布団から出られない日もある
Some days it's hard to get out of bed,
でも明日から そう明日から
but starting tomorrow, yes, starting tomorrow,
本気を出すんだ！
I'll give it my all!
気が済むまで 日が暮れるまで
Until I'm satisfied, until the sun goes down,
門限なんか無視で イッツ・オール・ライ！
ignoring any curfew, it's all right!
早起きよりも 徹夜しちゃおう
Instead of waking up early, let's stay up all night,
なんとかなっちゃうはずだから！
because it'll somehow work out!
ピンチはチャンスになるからさ
Because pinches turn into chances,
みんなで笑えば無敵だね
if we all laugh together, we're invincible.
なんだって全力で突き抜けちゃって！
With all our might, let's break through!
真っ直ぐな気持ちで行こう！
Let's go with straight, honest feelings!
ホップステップジャンプで飛び出そう！
Hop, step, and jump, let's leap out!
Yeah!!
ふふっ、ははっ！ ということで、始まりました！
Fufu, haha! So, it has begun!
えっと、これぬいホロライブ3期生の不知火フレアでーす！
Umm, I'm Shiranui Flare from Hololive 3rd Generation!
ふー、ちょっと1曲目にね、あの、この後すごくたくさん踊ると思ってちょっとラフに行こうと思ったったらね、あーこれはこれでしんどかった。
Phew, for the first song, I thought about taking it easy since we're going to dance a lot later, but man, this was tough in its own way.
めちゃめちゃ回って飛び回ってしまった！ ということで、私、今回、3周年ということでね、皆様、私の3周年記念ライブにお越しいただきまして、本当にありがとうございます！
I spun around and leaped all over the place! So, since this is my 3rd anniversary, thank you so much everyone for coming to my 3rd anniversary live!
ハッシュタグはこちら。
The hashtag is here.
このへんに出てると思うので、こちらのツイートをいっぱいしてください！お写真もバシバシバシバシ撮ってくれると嬉しいです。
It should be showing up around here, so please tweet a lot with it! I'd also be happy if you take lots of photos.
ま、今回はですね、あの、皆さんエルフレの私、そして今見てくれてる、え、初見の人とかね、あの、皆さんの記憶に残るライブの1つになると思うので、ぜひぜひ楽しんでくれると嬉しいです。
Well, this time, for everyone, my Elfure, and those of you watching for the first time, I think this will be one of those lives that stays in your memories, so I'd be really happy if you enjoy it.
さてさて、えー、2曲目なんですけど、2曲目はちょっとね、エルフレンドに手伝ってもらおうかなって思うんですよね。
Now, well, for the 2nd song, I think I'll ask the Elfriends to help me out.
ちょっと選ばれしエルフレンドを探したいので、ちょっとカメラさん、くるって回ってていいですか？
I want to find the chosen Elfriend, so camera-person, could you spin around?
どれどれ？どうかな？なんか、私の目に叶う、いいやついるかな？
Let's see. How is it? Is there someone who catches my eye?
おっ？きみ、あ、いいね！
Oh? You, ah, nice!
きみなんか死んだ魚の目をしている。いいじゃないか。
You look like you have dead fish eyes. That's pretty good.
おいで！こっちにおいで！
Come here! Come over here!
これはJP2期っぽいね。男の子かな？女の子かな？
This feels like JP Gen 2. Is it a boy? Or a girl?
まあまあ中性できそうな感じのエルフれんなわけだけど。
Well, it's an Elfure feeling like androgynous.
君は男の子？女の子？男の子？あ、男の子みたいですね。
Are you a boy? A girl? A boy? Ah, looks like a boy.
ということで、じゃあ、あの、今回はエルフレンド、え、JP2期にお手伝いしていただこうかなと思います。
So, well, this time, I'd like to have the Elfriend, JP Gen 2, help us out.
はい、代表だからね。みんなに恥ないように、みんなに恥ないように頼むで？
Right, because you're the representative. Please make sure you don't embarrass everyone, okay?
じゃあまずね、ちょっときみにはこれをプレゼント。これできみは社会の歯車になるんだよ。
So first, I'll present this to you. With this, you become a cog in society.
いいね？じゃあ、せーので見せるよ。はい、せーのっ！くるっ。
Got it? Then, I'll show it on 3. Ready, set! Spin.
ていうことで、え、今日はこの2人で1曲歌いおーぜ！
So, today the two of us will sing a song!
じゃあきみはこっち。はい、ということで、マイクも用意してくれたということでね、じゃあ早速なんですけど、2曲目行ってみよう！
Then you're over here. Right, so mics are prepared too, so let's go straight to the 2nd song!
ごいごいごいごい！すごい！ごいごいごい！
Goi-goi-goi-goi! Amazing! Goi-goi-goi!
あなたとあなたを幸せにする
Making you and you happy,
夢の夢のフレアチャンネル♪
The dream of a dream, Flare Channel!
僕は社会の歯車 労働環境is中の下の下 やりがい搾取給料据え置き コンビニアイスが贅沢です 在宅勤務でも社畜 ゆとりもZでも社畜 チクタク似ようなローテーション なんだかいいことないかなー
I'm a cog in society, working conditions at rock bottom, exploitation of passion, frozen wages, convenience store ice cream is a luxury, corporate slave even working from home, corporate slave whether Yutori or Gen Z, a ticking-like rotation, isn't there something nice going on?
「そこのおあなた！チャンスです！」
"You right there! It's your chance!"
チャンネル登録するだけでお届けしましょう日々の潤い 爆アゲ確定QOL これにて解決QED
Just by subscribing to the channel, delivering daily moisture, guaranteed hype QOL, solved with this QED
「はい、不知火コールセンターです」
"Yes, this is Shiranui Call Center."
なんかいいことないかなー
Isn't there something nice going on?
「そこのおあなた！チャンスです！」
"You right there! It's your chance!"
チャンネル登録
Subscribe to the channel
チャンネル登録するだけでお届けしましょう 日々の潤い
"Just by subscribing, I'll deliver daily refreshment!"
爆アゲ確定 QOL
Guaranteed hype, guaranteed QOL!
これにて解決 QED
Solved with QED!
「はい、不知火コールセンターです」
"Hello, this is the Shiranui Call Center."
将来が不安で
"I'm worried about the future."
なんとかなるでしょ
"It'll work out somehow!"
なんか寂しいんだ
"I feel kind of lonely..."
ゲームしよっよ
"Let's play games!"
声が届かない...
"My voice doesn't reach..."
コメント見てるよ
"I'm reading your comments!"
僕がいなくても...
"Even if I'm not here..."
君が必要だ
"I need you!"
ここに来れば 私はいる
If you come here, I'll be right here.
今日もバカみたいに騒ごうよ
Let's make foolish noise and party today too!
「今ならチャンネル登録なんと無料！」
"Right now, channel subscription is totally free!"
こんな時代だからこそ 僕とさんは出会えた
It's precisely because of times like these that you and I met.
距離も空間も次元も超えて 同じモーメント過ごしてるって
Crossing distance, space, and dimensions, sharing the exact same moment—
すごくない？ これはすごいことだよね
isn't that amazing? This is an incredible thing, right?
すごい！ すごい！ ここ！ ここ！ すごい！
Amazing! Amazing! Right here! Right here!
あなたと あなたを 幸せにする
I will make you and you happy!
夢の 夢の フレアチャンネル
The dream, the dream Flare Channel!
「フレアちゃんのおかげでおしゃれに目覚めました！」
"Thanks to Flare-chan, I've awakened to fashion!"
「フレアチャンネル見て詰みゲークリアできました！」
"Watching Flare Channel helped me clear an impossible game!"
「フレアチャンネルに入った日に宝くじ当たりました」
"I won the lottery the day I joined Flare Channel."
「フレアチャンネルを見始めてから膝が軽くなった気がします」
"Ever since I started watching Flare Channel, my knees feel lighter."
全てエルフレ個人の感想です
All testimonies are opinions of individual Elf-friends.
至近距離で言ってあげる みんなのことほんと大好きだー！
I'll tell you up close: I really, really love you all!
なんか晴れない世界も 君と僕なら 大丈夫さ
Even in a world that won't clear up, with you and me, we'll be fine.
地球爆誕で約5ビリオン やばいガチャ引き当てで出会えた
Earth's birth ~5 billion years ago, hitting the ultimate gacha to meet you!
やばくない？ やばくない？ やっぱやばいことだよ ね、やばいやばい
Isn't that crazy? Isn't it? It really is crazy, right? Crazy, crazy!
僕が僕でいられる そんな場所が ここなんだ
A place where I can just be myself—that's right here.
こんな時代だからこそ 僕とさんは出会えた
It's precisely because of times like these that you and I met.
距離も空間も次元も超えて 同じモーメント過ごしてるって
Crossing distance, space, and dimensions, sharing the exact same moment—
すごくない？ これはすごいことだよね
isn't that amazing? This is an incredible thing, right?
すごい！ すごい！ ここ！ ここ！ すごい！
Amazing! Amazing! Right here! Right here!
あなたと あなたを 幸せにする
I will make you and you happy!
夢の 夢の フレアチャンネル
The dream, the dream Flare Channel!
はーい！ ということでね
Hii! So, um...
どうだった？ 社会の歯車からは解放されたかい？
How was it? Were you liberated from the gears of society?
あ、そっか！ ならよかったね！ あーよかったよかった！ これで明日からもまたね、頑張れるね。
Ah, I see! Then I'm glad! Ah, I'm so glad! Now you can do your best again starting tomorrow.
はい、じゃあね、頑張ってくれたこのグラさんのね、エルフレには、拍手！盛大な拍手を！
Yes, so let's give a round of applause—a huge round of applause—to Kintsuba and all the Elf-friends who worked hard!
あ、こちらの曲はですね、エルフレンドと私とのデュエット、シャイさんになんと作っていただきました！ありがとうございます！
Ah, this song was actually created as a duet between Elf-friends and me by Shai-san! Thank you so much!
じゃあね、そのサングラスは記念に持って帰っていいからね！はい、それを付けてやる気に満ちあふれる生活を送ってくれよな！
Yeah, you can take those sunglasses home as a keepsake! Wear them and live a life full of motivation!
じゃあ、えー観客席に戻っておいで！ありがとう！
Alright, um, head back to the audience seats! Thank you!
ま、でもね、ちょっとね、やっぱ1人だけ、なんというかずるいよな。なんでね、まちょっとね、もうちょっとあの演奏してもらいたいんですよね、次のはね。エルフレンド何人か、あのステージからお呼びしたいんですけど、ちょっとまず私がサングラスを取りますね。
Well, but you know, having just one person is kind of unfair, right? So for the next song, I'd like to have a few Elf-friends join me on stage. But first, I'll take off my sunglasses.
まね、次の曲はね、もっと明るく...まあ明るかったけど今の、まちょっとね、あの次の曲は、私が君たちエルフレンドを応援する曲をね、送りたいなって思ってました。
Well, you know, the next song is much brighter... well, the last one was bright too, but um, for the next song, I wanted to send a song cheering all of you Elf-friends on.
日頃からみんなにね、何かプレゼントしたい、何かお返しできるものはないかなって思っていたので、今日はそれをやらせていただきたいなと思います。
I've always thought about wanting to give you all a present, something I could give back in return, so I'd love to do that today.
なんでね、ちょっと演奏してもらうエルフレンドを何人かお呼びさせていただきますです。ちょっとカメラをもっかい、くるっ...
So, I'll invite a few Elf-friends to perform. Let's spin the camera around once more...
えりぐらふぁーしん、な？
Eligraphers, huh?
で、あとは、えーっと、あ、EN、ENでいいね。
And then, um... EN, EN is fine too.
キミとキミと、あとJPも、もうちょっとほしいかな？
You and you, and JP, maybe a bit more?
キミとキミと、あ、なんか何者にも縛られていないオーソドックスなエルフレンドもいるね。
You and you, and orthodox Elfrien's too.
じゃあ、キミもいて。はい、ということで、
So you be here too. Right, so...
彼ら、彼女たちには、ちょっとね、次の曲を演奏していただこうかなって思って、準備できた？
I'm thinking of having them perform the next song. Are you ready?
はい、おいで、おいで、きたね。
Yes, come here, come here, you're here.
そしたらね、キミたちエルフレンド、おっ、なんか鼻飾りはじめてだね、かわいいね。
Then, you guys, Elfrien... Oh, flower ornaments for the first time, how cute.
はい、キミたちエルフレンドにもね、やっぱあの贈答品をプレゼントするからね。
Right, I should give gifts to you Elfrien's too.
はい、これをね、みんな、みんなちょっとこれをね持っててもらって...
Everyone, take this and hold it...
はい、できた？はい、これをね、じゃあ持っててもらって次の曲を演奏してもらうけど、いいか？はい、準備！
Alright, ready? Okay, hold this and play the next song—ready!
あ、いいね！はい、準備できました！
Ah, nice! Yes, ready!
じゃあ、彼女たちに演奏してもらいつつ、私がエルフレンドを応援するぞ！いきますよ！
While they perform, I will cheer on you Elfrien! Let's go!
さぁ、今日はエルフレンドのみんなを、応援するぞ！
Now, today I'll cheer on all the Elfrien!
覚悟してね！
Be prepared!
フレ！フレ！エルフレ！
Fure! Fure! Elfrien!
ガンバレガンバレエルフレ！
Ganbare ganbare Elfrien!
フレ！フレ！エルフレ！
Fure! Fure! Elfrien!
ガンバレガンバレエルフレ オー！
Ganbare ganbare Elfrien, oh!
朝はちょっとでも寝たい…なんて
Wishing I could sleep a bit more in the morning... or so
二度寝とスヌーズ、ループしてさ
Snoozing and going back to sleep in a loop,
朝だよ～！おはよーおはよー！
"It's morning~! Good morning, good morning!"
それでも毎朝起きてるキミは
Even so, you wake up every morning,
それだけでも表彰ものだ！
That alone deserves an award!
えらいぞ～！よしよしよしよしよし！
"Good job~! There, there, there, there!"
ときにはうまくいかずに凹んでしまうこともあるよね・
Sometimes things don't go well and you feel down, right...
それでもキミと私なら
Even so, with you and me,
きっと it's OK ! 乗り越えられるさ
I'm sure it's OK, we can overcome it!
さぁ、ハリきっていくよー！
Now, let's get fired up!
せーの！
Ready, set!
ぬいい！ぬいい！ぬいい！全力でエール送るよ (come on ! )
Nui! Nui! Nui! Sending you all my support (come on!)
キミをもっともっと元気にしたいんだ (ファイト！)
I want to make you even more energetic (fight!)
で、ぬいい！ぬいい！ぬいい！疲れたときはいつでもここに来てゆっくり休んだら
And, nui! nui! nui! Whenever you're tired, come here and rest a while,
一緒にまたやっていこうよ
And let's do our best together again!
ぬいい！ぬいい！ぬいい！
Nui! Nui! Nui!
フレ！フレ！エルフレ！
Fure! Fure! Elfrien!
ガンバレガンバレエルフレ！
Ganbare ganbare Elfrien!
フレ！フレ！エルフレ！
Fure! Fure! Elfrien!
ガンバレガンバレエルフレ！
Ganbare ganbare Elfrien!
今夜も帰りが遅くて一日すぐ終わっていくね
Tonight too, you get home late, and the day ends in a flash,
そんな日々の貴重なひと時を一緒にいてくれてありがとう
Thank you for spending these precious moments of such days with me!
平日、夜に大騒ぎ 歌って遊んで楽しんでね
Making a ruckus on a weekday night, singing, playing, and having fun!
そうして笑顔になったら きっと smile & go ! ! またがんばれるよ
And when you smile, I'm sure it's "Smile & Go!!" You can do your best again!
「めいっぱい楽しんでこー！」
"Let's enjoy ourselves to the fullest!"
せのぬいい！ぬいい！ぬいい！大丈夫何でもできるよ
Ready, nui! nui! nui! It's okay, you can do anything!
キミをもっともっと夢を描こう (ファイト！)
Let's dream even bigger together (fight!)
で、ぬいい！ぬいい！ぬいい！だからって無理しないでいつでも止まり木にいでよ
And, nui! nui! nui! That's why don't push yourself, always come back to your perch,
そっからまた始めよう
And let's start over from there!
日々のしんどさはループでも楽しさはきっとスパイラル
Even if daily hardship loops, joy is surely a spiral,
思い出っていう宝物手にしたら明日も怖くないよ
If you take hold of the treasure called memories, you won't be afraid of tomorrow either!
ぬいい！ぬいい！ぬいい！全力でエール送るよ
Nui! Nui! Nui! Sending you all my support!
キミをもっともっと元気にしたいんだ (ファイト！)
I want to make you even more energetic (fight!)
で、ぬいい！ぬいい！ぬいい！疲れたときはいつでもここに来てゆっくり休んだら
And, nui! nui! nui! Whenever you're tired, come here and rest a while,
一緒にまたやっていこうよ
And let's do our best together again!
ぬいい！ぬいい！ぬいい！
Nui! Nui! Nui!
フレ！フレ！エルフレ！
Fure! Fure! Elfrien!
ガンバレガンバレエルフレ！
Ganbare ganbare Elfrien!
フレ！フレ！エルフレ！
Fure! Fure! Elfure!
ガンバレ ガンバレ
Do your best! Do your best!
エールフレ！
Cheer up, Elfure!
いつもありがとう！
Thank you as always!
愛してるぞ！
I love you guys!
はーい！
Hi there!
てことでー、あ、エルフレンドの みんなを応援した、応援したー！
So, um, I wanted to cheer on all my Elfriends!
あー、疲れたー！
Ah, I'm exhausted!
でね、まだまだ続きますからね！
But hey, there's still more to come!
あ、今回歌わせていただいた曲は、髭ドライバーさんに作っていただきましたー！
The song I performed this time was made for me by Hige Driver-san!
エルフレンドをね、元気に応援したいなって思っていたので、もう理想的な曲ができたかなって思っています。
I wanted to cheerfully cheer on my Elfriends, so I think we made the ideal song.
エルフレンドの君たちはどうだった？
How was it for you Elfriends out there?
え、泣いて？あ、泣いてる？泣いちゃった？なんちゃって！
Huh, crying? Oh, you crying? Did you cry? Just kidding!
はい、ありがとうございます！いや、あのね、演奏してくれたみんなもね、ありがとね！
Yeah, thank you! And hey, thanks to everyone who played instruments too!
ありがとね！ありがとね！あ、ちょ、あ、やばい、女の子のエールフレンドにうつつをかした、ごめんね！
Thanks! Thanks! Oh wait, oh no, I got distracted by the girl Elfriends, sorry!
ありがと！ありがと！みんなありがとね！
Thanks! Thanks! Thank you everyone!
ま、まだまだね、あの、今回他にもたくさん曲歌うので、うん、今演奏してくれたみんなもね、あの、一旦ね、あの客席の方にお戻りいただいて
Well, there's still plenty more songs I'm gonna sing, so everyone who performed, please head back to the audience seating for now
次の曲をね、待ってほしいかなと思います！演奏してくれたエルフレンドたちに盛大な拍手！
and I hope you'll look forward to the next song! A huge round of applause for the Elfriends who performed!
ありがとー！ありがとー！ふふふふふ！
Thank you! Thank you! Hehehehe!
ありがとー！ありがとー！ふふふふふふ！
Thank you! Thank you! Fufufufufu!
帰っちゃった？あ、帰っちゃった。
They left? Oh, they left.
あ、これ、これ寂しいね！でもね、ちゃんと前にもね、エルフレンドがね
Ah, this, this is lonely! But you know, right in front of us, the Elfriends
二人演奏したり、あの、ぼーっとしたりとかしててくれるので
are playing together or spacing out or whatever,
え、私寂しくない！
so I'm not lonely!
僕にも、あ、あそこにも小さなエルフレンドがなんか今、演奏してくれてる
Even over there, there's a little Elfrend playing right now...
エルフレンドが見えましたね！
I could see the Elfrend!
はい、じゃあね、エルフレンドみんなね、いっぱいペンライト振るお仕事よろしくお願いしやすよ！
Right, so everyone, Elfriends, please keep up the good work waving your penlights!
はい、ではね、次はお待ちかねかと思うので、ま、あの曲をゲストのみんなと歌っちゃおうかなって思います！
Alright, well, next is probably what you've all been waiting for, so I think I'll sing that song together with our guests!
ゲストつってもね、ま、分かってるね！
When I say guests, well, you guys already know!
3期生のみんなと一緒にあの曲を歌うぞ！行ってみよう！
We're gonna sing that song together with all the 3rd gen members! Let's go!
こんのいー！準備はいいか？今日はみんなで騒ぎましょう！
Are you ready? Are you good? Let's all make some noise today!
せーの！はい！はい！はい！
Ready, go! Hey! Hey! Hey!
やってきたよみんなに会える時間です歌とかゲームとか見てほしくって
The time to meet everyone has come, 'cause we wanted you to watch us sing and play games!
あっという間に過ぎてしまう毎日塗り遅れないようにてくてくながーく
Days pass by in a blink, taking steps forward so we don't fall behind.
気づけばとなりにいてくれてありがとう
Thank you for always being right by my side before I knew it!
こんな高い壁だってひとっ飛びで飛び越えて誰も見たことない世界にみんなで行こうよ
Leaping right over such tall walls in a single bound, let's all go to a world no one has ever seen before!
君と Smile & Go!! 楽しんだもん勝ち 君と Smile & Go!! ハジけたもん勝ち
You & Smile & Go!! Whoever enjoys it wins! You & Smile & Go!! Whoever pops off wins!
ここに笑顔で集まれば最高でしょ Yeah!
If we gather here with smiles, it's the best, right? Yeah!
僕ら Smile & Go!! いつも全力で 僕ら Smile & Go!! 遊びまくろう
We & Smile & Go!! Always giving our all! We & Smile & Go!! Let's play our hearts out!
だってこの日常が大切な宝物だよ Smile & Go!!
Because this everyday life is our precious treasure! Smile & Go!!
ざっくばらん配信 今日はまったり行きましょう
Frank and open streaming, let's take it easy today!
かわいい話聞いてほしくて
Because we want you to listen to our cute stories
たまにはお休みしようと思ったけれどやっぱり晩酌配信しちゃおうかな
We thought about taking a break for once, but maybe we should do a drinking stream after all!
歩んできたこの時も一緒に過ごしたな
The times we've walked together, the moments we've spent side by side...
いつの間にかキラキラと何よりも輝いて抑えられない想いがあふれ出しちゃうよ
Before we knew it, shining brighter than anything else, feelings we can't hold back start overflowing!
君と Let's Enjoy! 語り合おうよ 君と Let's Enjoy! 宝物はひとつ
You & Let's Enjoy! Let's talk together! You & Let's Enjoy! Our treasure is one
どこにいたって優しさは届いてるよ Yeah!
No matter where you are, our kindness reaches you! Yeah!
僕ら Let's Enjoy! テンション上げてさ 僕ら Let's Enjoy! はしゃぎまくろうはきっと
We & Let's Enjoy! Raise the tension! We & Let's Enjoy! Let's party hard, surely
明日はもっと楽しいこと待っているから
tomorrow even more fun things are waiting for us!
こんぬいー！ 準備はいいかー！
Kon-nui! Are you ready?!
みんな3周年ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for 3 years!
こっから3千万こだー！
And 30 million more from here on out!
マリンいつもサンキューな！
Marine, thanks as always!
フレアこれからもよろしく！
Flare, let's keep having fun!
ペコラチェケラッチョ一緒来たよ！
Pekora, check it out, we came together!
みんなでね一緒にするよ！
Everyone together, ready, go!
チェケラ ワン ゴー！
3, 2, 1, GO!
ずっと見ていて 私のことを
Keep watching over me...
これから先も 期待してね
and look forward to the future!
予測不能なワクワクを 君に 送るから
Sending unpredictable excitement straight to you.
君とSmile & Go!! 楽しんだもん勝ち
With you, Smile & Go!! Whoever enjoys wins.
君とSmile & Go!! つけたもん勝ち
With you, Smile & Go!! Whoever puts it on wins.
ここに笑顔で 集まれば最高でしょ
Gathering here with smiles is the best, right?
僕らSmile & Go!! いつも全力で
We are Smile & Go!! Always giving our all,
僕らSmile & Go!! 遊びまくろう
We are Smile & Go!! Let's play to our hearts' content.
だって この日常が 大切な宝物だよ
Because this everyday life is a precious treasure.
飛び切りの笑顔でいこう Smile & Go!!
Let's go with the brightest smiles, Smile & Go!!
なにしよう？ 練習中？
What should we do? In practice?
しれっとこそっと準備進行 心情緊張手合わせる
Sneakily preparing in secret, hearts nervous, hands together.
理由ぼきゃ強気強気ありでしょう 元気配るからもうちょっと
Giving courage is fine, right? Spreading energy, so a bit more.
そうやって成長していく子です
That's how we keep growing.
いいかな？ ゆるっぽんでOK！ 1、2、3 げんぱっちゃってOK！
Is it okay? Relaxed is okay! 1, 2, 3, pop out and it's okay!
始めてじゃおう
Let's start it off!
ほめてほしいな ほめてほしいな ほめてくれたら2割増しで頑張る
I want you to praise me. If you praise me, I'll work 20% harder!
見ててほしいな 見ててほしいな ほめちぎられて伸びるタイプです
I want you to watch me. I'm the type who grows when praised!
もう！
Geez!
なにも出てこない 頭ん中真っ白だ サっぱりだ うんうんうん あれ？ ないか
Nothing comes to mind, my head is totally blank. Yup yup yup. Huh? Is there none?
てこぽこな情調提供
Providing clumsy emotions,
ポかんとしてなしっちょの こんなのが通常のアタシ
Standing blankly like that, this is my usual self.
いいでしょ それではOK！ 1、2、3 落ち着きOK！
Isn't it fine? Then it's okay! 1, 2, 3, calmness is okay!
始めてじゃおう
Let's start it off!
どうしたらいいの？ どうすればみんなハッピーで笑顔ばっちり
What should I do so everyone is happy with perfect smiles?
こちらへどうぞ こちらへどうぞ 焦らず慌てず並んで合図です
This way, please. Don't panic, don't rush, line up on the cue.
聞こえてる？
Can you hear me?
にゃんにゃんにゃん
Meow meow meow
楽しんでる
Are you enjoying it?
こっちだよ！
Over here!
少し眠いな 少し眠いな また明日食べて寝て 今日は成長期
A little sleepy. Eat and sleep again tomorrow, today is growth period.
夢を見たいな 夢を見たいな どうぞよろしくね あの今後も
I want to see dreams. Please treat me well from now on too.
ほめてほしいな ほめてほしいな ほめてくれたら2割増しで頑張る
I want you to praise me. If you praise me, I'll work 20% harder!
見ててほしいな 見ててほしいな ほめちぎ
I want you to watch me, watch me. Praised to high...
あはははは！
Ahahaha!
最後まで、はくっ…
Until the very end...
電池がね、切れちまったということで、
Our batteries ran out, so...
フレア！
Flare!
ノエル！
Noel!
あ！切れちゃう！
Ah! It's cutting out!
もう一回！切れちゃう！
Once more! It cut out!
いつもフレアにさ、そういうのされてるから、私もね、ちょっとやりたいなって思って。
Flare always does that to me, so I wanted to try it too.
いや、この度はおめでとうございます！
Congratulations on this occasion!
今回のライブ、いやめっちゃかっこいいじゃん！
This live concert is so cool!
何？スカイソナー？
What? Sky Sonar?
そうなんです、青空をテーマにしてみまして。青い空！そして海！
That's right, we made the blue sky our theme. Blue sky! And ocean!
いや、うちらがね、デビューしたのが夏、まっさかりでさ。
We debuted right in the middle of summer.
いや、まぶしい！眩しすぎて溶け、溶けちまうぜ！
So dazzling! It's blindingly dazzling!
お前もその一部分なんだぜ！
You're part of it too!
いや本当さ、すごいエモいんですけど。
It's really emotional.
え、この中だと団長はこれ、あ、これしてる？
In this, is the captain doing this?
そうだよ。
That's right.
いやなんか、いいね。でもね、あれ多分誰にも当たってないから、
It's nice. But nobody's hit by it, right?
「ネエルがそっ…」っていうの、ちょっとしんみり過ぎないか？
Saying "Noel is..." is a bit too melancholic.
いやいいね、ちょっと、あれですよ、4周年目もね、そのしんみりね、よろしくお願いいたします。
Well, please treat us well for the 4th year too.
漫才ですか？
Is this a manzai?
漫才始まってね。
A manzai started.
いや、本当にありがとうございます！
Congratulations indeed!
いやなんかさ、ほめのディ、めちゃくちゃ人気ある曲じゃないですか！
Flare's Praise is a super popular song!
あ、ありがとうございます！結構ね、ほめのが歌わくとかで歌ってくれて。いやまさか、フレアとこうやって2人で歌って踊れるなんて！
Thank you! Flare sings it in streams, but I never thought we'd sing and dance together!
この日のために！そして今まで歌わなかったわけじゃないですから。
For this day! It's not like we haven't sung it until now.
あ、なるほど。そういうわけではないんですけどね、もちろんね。
Ah, I see. Not that we couldn't, of course.
そういう言うと、ちょっと、変わってくるからね。歌ってなかったから焦って歌ったんかみたいななっちゃうからね。
If you say that, people might think we panicked and sang it.
違うね、違うね、違うね！
No, no, no!
え、ねえ、ねえ、ねえ、ほめ、ほめて、ほめて、ほめて。
Praise, praise me, praise me!
こんな感じ実際踊るとなかなか合わないの、ここが。
Actually dancing together, it's hard to sync up here.
あ、ここね！いな、いな、ちょっと、こう。
Ah, here! Wait, wait, like this.
あでもここさ、あれかもしれない、エルフレの皆とか団員さんとかがこの間にいるかも知れない。寄せないけど。
Maybe Elfrends and danin-san are between us. Though we don't bunch up.
そうだね、びっしゃ、寄せないけどねって。
That's right, we don't bunch up.
いや本当にエモいな。でしょ？エモすぎる。
It's really emotional. Right? Too emotional.
みんなで写真撮っとく？
Shall we take a photo together?
団員さんと、エルフレンドの写真撮るか。脳が破壊されるところ。
Let's take a photo with danin-san and Elfrends. Brain-breaking moment.
団員さんと、エルフレンドと写真撮るか。
Let's take a photo with danin-san and Elfrends.
ちょっと脳が破壊されるところじゃなくて。ピース！いやまだまだ続くのね。
Brain-breaking moment? Peace! It still continues.
そう、まだまだ続くからね。ピース見てね。まだまだ続くぞ！イェーイ！
That's right, it still continues. Peace! It keeps going! Yay!
体力なら充分！
Plenty of stamina!
踊り疲れるよーほー！
Dancing until we drop, yo-ho!
さあ、今旗の下へ！
Now, beneath the flag!
発進！我ら宝鐘海賊団！
Launch! We are the Houshou Pirates!
出航！ Ahoy!
Set sail! Ahoy!
踊る Ahoy! 見る Ahoy!
Dancing Ahoy! Watching Ahoy!
全速前進だー！
Full speed ahead!
すすめ！すすめ！
Advance! Advance!
太陽は燦々、大公開日よりだ！
The sun is bright, a great day for sailing!
歌え！歌え！
Sing! Sing!
最高のテンション波の音に乗せてドンブラコカー！
High tension riding on the waves, donburakoka!
海でガールズトーク！
Girls' talk by the sea!
岡で兄貴がハッピー！
Aniki is happy on land!
踊り疲れてはグラグラ、ひらひら～
Getting dizzy from dancing, fluttering~
夢を夜をボロボロマイハウスで夢を見て…
Dreaming dreams in my worn-out house...
神様！いつかこのマリーを本物の海賊にしてやってください！
God! Please make this Marie a real pirate someday!
はいっ！
Aye!
声を上げて！さあ、出航だ我ら宝鐘海賊団！
Raise your voices! Set sail, Houshou Pirates!
コンパス片手に旗を掲げ、この海をジャックしちゃおう！
Compass in hand, hoisting the flag, let's jack this ocean!
夜空を辿って、おいで一緒に！よーほー！よーほー叫ぼう！
Following the night sky, come together! Yo-ho! Shout yo-ho!
ああ、最高のの日々！
Ah, the best days!
夜を航す我が船！
Our ship sailing through the night!
出航！ Ahoy! 踊る Ahoy! 見る Ahoy!
Set sail! Ahoy! Dancing Ahoy! Watching Ahoy!
ド・キ・ド・キ・して rouge？
Do, ki, do, ki, make it rouge?
いきましょう～！
Let's go!
無罪！
Innocent!
美少女無罪！
Innocent beautiful girl!
マリン！
Marine!
マリンは無罪！
Marine is innocent!
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
Still sparkling, even more dizzying!
ねぇ、言ったよね？
Hey, didn't you say so?
年齢なんて関係ないってさ
That age has nothing to do with it!
出航──！！
Departure──!!
キュートは正義 美少女無罪
Cute is justice, innocent beautiful girl!
キミの一番目指して ヨーソロー！
Aim for your number one, yorosoro!
本当は自信ないけど 頑張っちゃう
I'm actually not confident, but...
ahoy！！
Ahoy!!
きゅっきゅっきゅるん 恋する気持ち 17歳
Thumping, thumping, thumping, thumping! Feelings of love, seventeen years old.
0時（てぺん）になっちゃうワ
It turns 0 o'clock (tepen)?
オトナの時間
Adult time!
はっ、神さま！船長は船長でまたっ
Gosh, Captain's already like that,
凡されちゃうのですねぇ！
so we're going to run out of time!
はにゃあ！
Hanya!
奪われたら取り戻せ
If it's stolen, take it back,
それが保証 最高のキミたちとなら辿り着ける
that's our guaranteed, ultimate compass!
伝説のエルドラド！
The legendary El Dorado!
やぁさろ、楽しけりゃ歌えよほよほ
Hey guys, let's have fun and sing!
足りないあぁこの景色
There's no shortage of scenery like this!
大切な仲間よ！
Daisetsu na nakama yo!
歌えや歌え 騒げや騒げ
Singing, singing, making a fuss, making a fuss!
踊るぁ ahoy！ 見るぁ ahoy！
Dancing, ahoy! Seeing, ahoy!
同じ ahoy ならのまんなか 33！
The same ahoy, isn't that right, san san!
高掲げる片手に行きますよ それ ahoy！
We're going with one raised hand!
ahoy！ ahoy！ ahoy！ ahoy！
Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy!
宝鐘マリン！宝鐘マリン！
Houshou Marine! Houshou Marine!
世界で一番可愛いよ！
The cutest in the world!
メスガキ！メスガキ！
Bratty! Bratty!
エロガキ！エロガキ！
Lewd brat! Lewd brat!
番きゅっぱ！番きゅっぱ！
Banchou! Banchou!
お嬢ちゃん 罰は何色？
Ojou-chan, what's with the punishment game?
罰入ってます！
Punishment accepted!
おっから おっから 撫でず 撫でず ドーン！
Warm, warm, warm, warm, stroking, stroking, stroking, stroking!
「見てみたい～！」
"I'd love to see that!"
もっと！もっと！もっと！
More, more, more, more!
セクシービーム！
Sexy beam!
もっと もっと もっと！ いや、まいっちんぐ！
Motto, motto, motto! Yeah, fighting, woo!
タッチの… もーっと もーっと もーっと！ ドキドキする！
Touch! Touch! Touch! Touch! Doki, doki, doki!
もえもえキュン！
Moemoe-kyun!
出会って5秒で即出航～！
Meet and five seconds for immediate departure!
あー、もう！船長は君たちをそんな子に育てた覚えはありません！
Oh, no, Captain, I don't remember raising you to be like that.
本当にか？ねぇ、だぞ！
Really? Did you?
「座れば地獄、座れば昭和。歩く姿は戦士風」
"If you sit on the ground, history will walk."
夢を見よう この船で 後悔なんてさせない
Let's see our dreams on this ship, we'll never let you regret it!
キミたちのおかげで私は船長になれるから ミラクル船長だな！撃てーーーっ！
Thanks to you guys, I can be a captain! Miracle Captain! Shoot!
声を上げて最終出航だ
Raise your voice and make it a final voyage!
われら保証 最高のコンパス片手に旗を上げ この海をジャックしよっ
Raise the flag in one hand with our guaranteed, ultimate compass, and conquer this sea!
よぉからついておいで共によぉほよぉ叫ぼう
Come on, follow us, let's shout together, hoy hoy!
あぁ最高の日にようこそ我が船へ この昭和の海賊だー！
Welcome to the best days on the pirate ship! This is the pirate's song!
それでは行きますよ！ つっこ！やぁそろ！
Here we go! Tsukko! Yorosoro!
あぁ、気持ちよかったー！ あ、ちょっとさ、船長のセリフでしょ、最後のは。
Ah, that felt good! Ah, wait a second, Captain's speech at the very end was...
なんか、やっぱさ、私の船かなって気がしちゃって。 お前、船なんて持ってないんです！
You know, I kinda felt like it was my ship. What? You don't even have a ship!
ちょっと勘違いしちゃったとは気持ち良くなかった。 それでは行きますよ、しゅっこうー！
You misunderstood, it didn't feel good. Well then, let's go, shukko!
しゅっこうー！ 声でけえな、ちょっと。
Shukko! I can't even say it right!
いやぁ、船長、おめでとう3周年！ ありがとうございます！ふーっ！うぇーい！
Yeah, congratulations on your third anniversary! Thank you! Whoo!
マリンももうすぐじゃん。 あ、そうなんだよね。 すぐそこだからね。
Marine is almost there too. Ah, that's right, yeah. It's right around the corner, so...
私たち3期生はみんなね、デビューが近いからね。 3年経ってみて思うけどさ、
We three-period students all have debuts close to each other. Even after three years, though, Flare...
なんかフレアと最近遠いって感じる。 でも遠くしたのはお前やろ！
It feels like I've drifted far from Flare recently. Well, you're the one who made distance, idiot!
たしかに。 うるさいし、そんなことないよねえ！
True. Shut up, there's no such thing!
最近ねなんかラミィと仲がいいとかさ、なんか。 なんかいつも声かけてんのって船長ばっかりな気がする。
Lately, it feels like Ramy and the others are closer... You always call out to them while it feels like you only ever call out to the captain.
え？そんなことないよ！ なんか船長ばっかり声かけてる気がするなぁ。
Eh? No way! It feels like you only ever call out to the captain!
でもね、なんかマリンは都合のいい女にしか話しかけないからね。 なにその、やめろやめろ！どういう意味や！
Well, you know, Marine only talks to women who suit her convenience. What kind of... stop it, stop it! What's that supposed to mean?
船長、それは本当だ。 それは本当でもいいと。
Captain, well, that's the truth. That's true? Well, that's fine too.
時間がないからね。 あ、はいはい。 そう、あの、ほら、お泊まりの時にさ、
Because you don't have time, right? Yeah, yeah, yeah. So, you know, when we went on the tour,
あの、アホイをさ、歌ったことがあるんだけどさ、 実は、こんなちゃんと歌ったの初めてだったんだよ。
we sang "Ahoy," and I've sung it before, but actually, this is the first time I've sung it this properly.
ちゃんとこうやってパートを分けてしっかり。 そうそうそう。で、しかもね、絶対シマバトを真面目に歌わないっていうね。
Yeah, singing it properly with parts separated like this. Yeah, yeah, and besides, I never seriously sing Shima-bato.
なんか、あの、なんか、あのさ、暇にならないんだよね、どっちも。 座れば地獄のパートの、あの声何ですか、突然。
It's just that neither of us can take it seriously! Flare, the part about "Sit on the ground," what is that voice?
あの声何やねん！ え、だって、そういうふうに歌ってって、マリンが。 あそこも森戻れよだからねって言ってて。 そう、座れば。
What is that voice?! Well, because I sang it like that, Marine got... Ah, that's because I told you to go back to the forest. Yeah, sit on the ground.
立てばちょ… ちがうわ。
"Tatebacho..." No, wait.
たてばちょ…
Tatebacho...
なんか、歩く姿は、なん、そんなんじゃなかったさっき！
Wait, your walking posture wasn't like that just now!
え、そう？ 立てばちょみたいな感じだった？
Eh, really? It looked like "tatebacho" or something?
え、変だった？ 変だった？
Eh, was it weird? Was it weird?
いやこれはリベンジしないといけないね、フレア。
Man, we gotta get revenge for this, Flare.
また…また次やりないと。
We gotta do it again next time.
そうだね、また来年…
That's right, next year...
リベンジしようね。
let's get our revenge.
なんできねんナン？
Wait, why next year?
ねえねえ、別に来年じゃなくても今年中にまだまだリベンジできるよね？
Hey hey, we don't have to wait till next year, we can still get revenge this year, right?
え、ほんとに？ マネージャーにやる気あるの？
Eh, really? Does the manager even have the motivation?
あるよ。
I do.
ほらこんな近くにいる。
Look, they're right here close by.
よく考える…今年さ…あれ？コラボしたっけ？
Come to think of it... this year... wait, did we collab?
したよ！ 時系列的に言うともうマリフレお泊まり会があったあとだからここは…この時系列だからいま…
We did! Chronologically speaking, since the MariFure sleepover already happened...
ま、まだしてないけど今年中に何回やったかもしれないぐらいです。
Well, we haven't yet, but we might have done it a few times already this year.
まだやるな！
Don't say "still do it"!
ねえ！ これからも、これからもやろうな。
Hey! Let's keep doing it in the future.
ちょっとペコマリ、ペコマリ義務コラボする前に、マリフレ義務コラボしないと。 義務じゃないよね？
Before doing a PekoMarine mandatory collab, we gotta do a MariFure mandatory collab. Not that it's mandatory, right?
あ、じゃあマリのジムに付き合いますっていう、どうしたの？ どうしたの今日？
Ah, then "I'll accompany Marine to the gym"—wait, what's wrong? What's up with you today?
あのちょ、あの1期生のみんなとの写真撮ろっか？
Um, hey, shall we take a picture with all the 1st gen members?
あ、そっ、え、あ、ちがちがちが。
Ah, wait, eh, no no no.
あっち？ あっち？
Over there? Over there?
そう。
Yeah.
あ、そういうこと？ そう。 いぇーい！
Ah, is that what you mean? Yeah. Yay!
いぇーい！ はい、きむ、きむまりふれでした！
Yay! That was Kim- Kimarifure!
じゃあ次が、次は誰ですか？
Well then, who's next?
え、ペコちゃんのところに、ペコちゃんのところに…
Um, at Peko-chan's place...
しっ…しまらない。 え、ペコちゃんのところに…
Sh- it doesn't fit. Um, at Peko-chan's place...
に…しゅっか…？ しゅっか…？ しゅっか…？
Ni- shukka...? Shukka...? Shukka...?
出発！
Departure!
あ、いかないで！ 来てくれるんだ。 ペコちゃんなんだけどな。
Ah, don't go! You're coming. Even though it's Peko-chan.
どっちが好きなのよ！
Which one do you like the best?!
なんだかさみしぃ 気持ちはチモシー
Feeling real lonely, emotions like timothy grass.
あの娘にゃ負けない 毛羽立ってジェラシー
I won't lose to that girl, all fluffy and jealous.
言わなきゃってわかってる
I know I have to tell this to you,
ああでもない こうでもない
but it's not like this or like that.
やめにしましょう
Let's just stop it.
つらぬき my my my mind
Run through my my my mind!
聞きたくない！ いいわけバニー
I don't want to hear it! You excuse-making bunny!
地団駄 no！ 優柔不断 だんだん
No more stomping! More and more indecisive!
ハニーバニー だりーだりー
Honey bunny, so tiring, so tiring!
マジな話 どっちが好きなのよ！
Seriously speaking, which one do you like the best?!
(ダメダメダメ) よそみしないで
(No way!) Don't look away!
(ダメダメダメ) もう逃げ出したいのは私のほう
(No way!) I'm the one who wants to escape!
(でしょでしょ？) 通しませんはんたいほうこう
(Right? Right?) A dead end! Go the other way!
wanted！ いいわけバニー どこへだって行けばいい
Wanted! Excuse bunny, go wherever you want!
聞きたくない！ いいわけバニー
I don't want to hear it! You excuse-making bunny!
地団駄 no！ 優柔不断 だんだん
No more stomping! More and more indecisive!
ハニーバニー だりーだりー
Honey bunny, so tiring, so tiring!
マジな話 どっちが好きなのよ！
Seriously speaking, which one do you like the best?!
(ダメダメダメ) よそみしないで
(No way!) Don't look away!
(ダメダメダメ) もう逃げ出したい けどやるしかない
(No way!) I want to escape, but I've got no choice!
(でしょでしょ？) 通しませんはんたいほうこう
(Right? Right?) A dead end! Go the other way!
wanted！ いいわけバニー そばにいて いいわけバニー
Wanted! Excuse bunny, stay by my side, excuse bunny!
大とくい！は、大得意！ 興味がないから超苦手
Very proud! Well, super proud! Since I have no interest, I'm super bad at it.
糸の切れた凧揚げと 貼り紙届きゴミ
Like flying a kite with a snapped string, or a notice for trash.
きっと私並み 荒ぶってポエニ
Just like me, wild and raging,
精神あるのみ 荒ぶってエネミー
Only spirit left, raging at the enemy,
聖戦なんて あんなのやっちまいなさい！
Holy wars and such, just go ahead and do it!
疲れてちゃった人休み なんとかね やってよね
Tired people take a break, manage somehow and do it,
あしたの私 任せてよ マイマイマイマイ
Leave tomorrow's me to it! My-my-my-my!
決められない！
Can't decide!
いいわけバニー うーやむやげ
Excuse-making bunny, wishy-washy,
ユーモアがどくさつ
humor is tyrannical,
めでめにごににまにがちな話し方 how much?
eye to eye, eye to eye, everyday talk, how much?
オトシマエ！
Pay the price!
あした飯前です
Tomorrow is right before meals,
そんなのってない 私一途なほう じゃでしょ？
That's not fair! I'm the devoted type, right?
買い水 逃がさない！
Buy water, won't let you escape!
どこへだって行けばいい
Go wherever you want!
いいわけない よーしゃしない
No way! No mercy!
冗談じゃない ぶつけろ
Not kidding, collide it!
マイマイマイマイ 決められない！
My-my-my-my, can't decide!
聞きたくない！
I don't want to hear it!
いいわけバニー
Excuse bunny!
地団駄 no！ 優柔不断 だんだん
No more stomping! More and more indecisive!
ハニーバニー だりーだりー
Honey bunny, so tiring, so tiring!
マジな話 どっちがどっちが
Seriously speaking, which is which,
好きなのよ！
which one do you like?!
よそみしないで
Don't look away!
もう逃げ出したい けどやるしかない
I want to escape, but I've got no choice!
通しませんはんたいほうこう
A dead end! Go the other way!
wanted！ いいわけバニー そばにいて いいわけバニー
Wanted! Excuse bunny, stay by my side, excuse bunny!
どっちが好きなのよ！
Which one do you like?!
あのお方に負けない毛羽立ってジェラシー
Jealousy bristling so I won't lose to her!
ねえ、最後のハート合ってないように見える！
Hey, it looks like our final hearts didn't match up!
すごい！この呼吸のさ、このダンスをさ、ふたりがぴったり呼吸良くなってもうこうなってたじゃん！
Amazing! Like, our breathing in this dance got so in sync, but it ended up like this!
船や、船や！3周年おめでとう！ありがとう！
A ship! A ship! Happy 3rd anniversary! Thank you!
ぺこらもおめでとう！ありがとう！
Congrats to you too, Pekora! Thank you!
いや3期生はさ、みんなこのタイミングだからね。
Man, the 3rd gen all happened to be around this timing, right?
え、そう、ぺこらだよねえ。
Yeah, that's right, Pekora.
いやおめでたい！夏はね、熱いぺこらなんだよねやっぱり。
Congrats! Summer is when Pekora gets really fired up, you know.
熱いね！気持ちも高ぶるわけですよ。
So hot! Our spirits get all hyped up too.
早いもんで3年経っての活動して。
It's been already 3 years of activities.
そうだよ！でなんかフレアとぺこーらがさ、なんだろう、結構話もいい感じでさ。
That's right! And Flare and Pekora, our chats have been going really well.
いいよ！いいの！てかぺこーらがすごいフレアとさ、最初にコラボしたのなんだか覚えてる？
Good! It's good! Remember when Pekora first collaborated with Flare and what it was?
マイクラ？
Minecraft?
あ、そうだ！マインクラフトだ！火薬集めペコで、懐かしいね！
Ah, that's right! Minecraft! Gathering gunpowder, how nostalgic!
ねえ、そのペこらさ、あのころは、なんかマインクラフトともにさ、初心者だったよね、あの初めてだったもんね。
Hey, back then Pekora was a total beginner at Minecraft, it was our first time.
なのに、いまとなってはさ、ペコラたちも結構、なかなかマインクラフトやってる、立ち位置になってるからさ。
Yet now, Pekora and I are in positions where we play a lot of Minecraft.
あのときのペコラはさ、めちゃめちゃ過激でさ、今すっかり丸くなっちまったな！
Back then, Pekora was so hardcore, but now you've totally mellowed out!
ちょっと待てよ！それを言うなら、私がしてたペコラをね、あれもうアンディゲーターの巣にさ
Hold on a second! If you're going to say that, the Pekora I knew...
マグマを流し込むみたいな、あーいうことをね、平気でやっちゃうやつだったんだけどね、今はね。
Doing stuff like pouring magma into nests without a care in the world, but now...
みんなで探検行くペコ！みたいに、すっかり丸くなりがって！
"Let's all go on an adventure, Peko!" You've gotten totally soft!
え、ちゃんと待ってペコで、いや、まだペコラも過激なところあるペコで！
Wait a minute! No, Pekora still has her hardcore moments!
まる、えでも、丸くなってる、そうだなぁ、TNT爆弾ぐらいかな。
Well, maybe you've mellowed out, like, down to TNT bombs level.
おい！なんだよそれ！もっと過激なこと、やらなきゃいけないペコ！
Hey! What's that supposed to mean?! We gotta do even more wild stuff!
でもおね、最近とかね、ぺこちゃんと一緒にさ、あの、まあ突発的だけどさ、あの...
But you know, recently, like doing spontaneous collabs with Peko-chan, um...
モンハン？そう！モンハンもやってじゃん！めちゃめちゃ楽しかった！
Monster Hunter? That's right! We played Monster Hunter too! It was so much fun!
めちゃくちゃ楽しかったよね！なんかさ、コラボそんなふたりでとかしないぺこじゃん？
It was super fun! We don't usually collab just the two of us, right?
なんかね、たぶんふたりともね、そんなにコミュ力じゃないからさ、あの、予定立てるっていうのが苦手なんだよね。
Probably because neither of us is very sociable, so planning things ahead is not our strong suit.
いや、あんたさ、コミュ力じゃない？あんた。
Wait, aren't you sociable? You are.
え、違う違う。だって誘ってないじゃん。あ、確かに誘われてない。
Huh? No way. You didn't invite me. Ah, true, I wasn't invited.
そうそうそうそう、だから、なんかあの、来て、来てくれるかな、ちらちら、みたいな感じなんだよね、ふたりとも。
Exactly, so it's like, "Will they come, will they invite me?" kind of glancing back and forth between us.
あ、そうあれしかをさ、なんだっけ、フレアのさ、あの、この前のライブのときもさ、あの、今年やれたらいいねとか言ってたじゃん。
Oh right, regarding Shikao, what was it, during Flare's previous live too, you said "hope we can do it this year."
いやマジ今年1回はさ、絶対さ、対面でやろうぜペコだよ。
Seriously, we definitely gotta do it in person at least once this year, Peko.
りたいね！絶対ね！
I want to! Definitely!
だからちらちらしないで誘ってくれよ！いやあんたも誘えないよ、ペこじゃなくて！
So stop giving side-eye and just invite me! No, you can't invite either, Peko!
誘う、誘う。よろしくね、じゃあ。そろそろあれかな？
I'll invite you. Sounds good, then. Is it about time?
あ、そう、そうなんだよね。もう時間な...あ、しゃし、イエーイ！
Ah, right, that's right. It's time... ah, photo, yay!
あ、こっち、こっちで写真撮って、解散しよう。オッケー！
Ah, let's take a picture over here and wrap up. Okay!
じゃあ、イエーイ！ペこペコ！ペこペコ！
Alright, yay! Peko-peko! Peko-peko!
ということで、そろそろお時間ですかね？
With that said, is it about time?
うん、じゃあ、そろりお帰り？
Yep, time to head back?
はい。これにてぺこら、ペこペこペコ...
Yes. With that, Pekora, peko-peko-peko...
世界の果ての
At the world's edge,
大いなる樹の竈より
from the hearth of the great tree,
永遠の果てへ旅立つは歌声
a song voice embarks toward eternity's end.
季節は巡りて種はいつか芽生えて
Seasons turn, and seeds will one day sprout,
見守り見送り花は実を残す
watched over, seen off, as flowers leave their fruit.
時の水面に消えてゆく名を
The name fading upon the surface of time,
ただ一人だけ覚えていよう
let us remember, just one person alone.
ここに誰かが 確かにいたと
Someone was surely here,
古の調べは
the ancient melody
明日も歌うだろう
will keep singing tomorrow too.
海原を行く
Crossing the ocean wide,
風を追う海賊の譚詩
a pirate's ballad chasing the wind.
荒野を歩む
Walking the wilderness,
誇り高き騎士の頌歌
a proud knight's ode.
兎を追って落ちた穴には 世界の秘密記されている
In the rabbit hole I fell down, the secrets of the world are inscribed.
過去も未来も幻だから
Since past and future are both illusions,
いつでも君に会いにいけるよ
I can go meet you anytime.
季節は巡って
Seasons turn and pass,
友は先に行き
my friend went on ahead,
見守り 見送り いつも残されて
watching over, seeing them off, always left behind.
君の屍を 森に還そう
Let's return your remains to the forest,
いつか世界樹の 元で会う
to meet again someday at the foot of Yggdrasil.
その時までは さよならだから
Until that time, it's a temporary farewell,
一粒の涙を
shedding a single tear.
時の水面に消えてゆく名を ただ一人だけ覚えていよう
I will be the only one to remember the name fading on the surface of time.
ここには君が 確かにいたと
You were surely here,
古の調べは 生きた証を
and the ancient melody—proof that you lived—
明日も歌うだろう
will keep singing tomorrow too.
世界の果ての
At the edge of the world,
大いなる樹を 讃えて歌おう
let's praise and sing to the great tree.
保険 言い訳は撒いて 横切った未来 ブレッドフォークにくれてやらないよ
Spreading insurance and excuses, I won't give away the future I crossed.
未知数が憧れに 絡まったって奪えはしない
Even if unknowns entangle with longing, no one can steal it away.
空を創ろう
Let's create the sky,
散らかったパズル 組み合わせてても足りない
even if I piece together the scattered puzzle, it's not enough.
壁に写した 知らない世界の 前にあった重い扉開け
Open the heavy door that was before a world unknown, projected on the wall.
忘れてた 少年の絵のように
Like a forgotten boy's drawing,
温度は高く 微熱まじりで 夢話していたい
I want to keep talking about dreams with a high temperature and a slight fever.
もう憧れは 描き飽きて
I'm tired of drawing my longings,
全部を見るため 空いたアトリエ
an empty atelier to see everything—
空いたアトリエ 帰るアトリエ いつかは
an empty atelier, an atelier to return to, someday.
想像して かきなぐって塗り替えても外をもっと進んでいた
Even if I imagine, scribble, and repaint, the outside had moved even further ahead.
不揃いな景色の中 棘が刺さっても走ってみたい
Inside uneven scenery, even if thorns pierce me, I want to try running.
道を創ろう 遠くなるほど
Let's make a path, the farther it gets,
細く薄れてて描けない
the thinner and fainter it becomes, unable to be drawn.
イメージをした 近い未来ぼやけたら 重い扉開け
If the near future I imagined gets blurry, open the heavy door
その心 大胆に染めよう
and dye that heart boldly.
いつかの絵さえ 霞くくらいの夢生み出したい
I want to create a dream so vivid it overshadows even drawings of the past.
成果なんて わからない
Not knowing if there will be any results,
きっとそれでも 去ったアトリエ
surely even then, an atelier left behind...
僕のアトリエ
My atelier
いつでも
Anytime
どれだけ濡れても
No matter how wet it gets,
擦ったって消えない
rubbing it won't make it disappear.
戻せない
Can't go back,
現実は鮮やか
reality is vivid.
忘れてた少年の絵のように
Like a forgotten boy's painting,
温度は高く微熱まじりで夢話していたい
I want to talk of dreams, warm with a slight fever.
もう憧れは描き飽きて
Tired of drawing longing,
全部を見るため空いたアトリエ
an empty atelier to see it all.
空いたアトリエ
An empty atelier,
帰るアトリエ
an atelier to return to,
いつかは
someday...
はい、てことでね、聞いていただきました、2曲続けて聴いていただきました、楽曲の紹介させてください。
Right, so, we just listened to two songs back-to-back, let me introduce the songs.
えー、ユグドラシル、こちら未来古代楽団さんに作っていただきました。
Um, "Yggdrasil", this was made by Mirai Kodai Gakudan.
そしてアトリエ、こちらも渡辺翔さんに作っていただきました。
And "Atelier", this was also made by Sho Watanabe.
私の大好きなアーティストさんに今回たくさん曲を作っていただけて、もう本当に本当に幸せです。
I'm so, so happy that my favorite artists made so many songs for me this time.
まあね、も皆さそして、えーエルフレンドたちにも本当に本当に感謝です。
Well, and to everyone, and to my Elfren, I'm truly, truly grateful.
では次がですね、最後の曲になってしまうんですけど、
Well, the next one will be the last song,
あの、その前にですね、あの、グッズの告知もありますので、こちらもですね、あの、噂の数量限定はあるのかないのか、最後までですね、ちゃんと見ててくれると嬉しいなって思ってます。
but before that, there's a merchandise announcement, so I hope you'll watch until the very end to see if there's any talk of a limited quantity.
ではですね、最後の曲を、え、歌いたいなと思います。
So, I'd like to sing the last song.
この曲はですね、本当にいろんな思い出があるんですけれども、本当になんか大好きなアーティストさん、そしてそれを締めくくるのはこちらのサブタイトルにもなっております、「スカイソナー」。
This song has so many memories, and the one that wraps it up is our subtitle as well, "Sky Sonar".
この曲を描いてくださったのは、奥華子さんです！本当にありがとうございました！
The one who wrote this song is Hanako Oku! Thank you so much!
こちらですね、コーラスまでみんなしっかりお聴き逃しのく、では、歌わせていただきます、最後の曲、みんな今日来てくれて本当にありがとうございました！
For this one, everyone listen closely to the chorus as well—well, I'll let you hear it, the last song, thank you so much for coming today!
四角い画用紙に大きな丸を描いたら
If you draw a large circle on a square sheet of drawing paper,
はしっこ少しずつかけてしまった思い散りり
feelings that chipped away at the edges scatter and fall apart.
大人になったらきっと綺麗に描けると思っていたんだ
When I became an adult, I thought I'd be able to draw it beautifully.
人生100年なんて言うようになっても
Even as they start talking about a 100-year lifespan,
子供でいられるのはたった20年なんだし
you can only be a child for a mere 20 years.
もっとゆっくり大人になってもいいんじゃない自分にがっかりしないように
Wouldn't it be okay to become an adult more slowly, so as not to be disappointed in yourself?
どこにもないものは誰もまだ知らないだけ
Things that exist nowhere else are simply things no one knows yet.
形も名前も自由に掲げていいんだ
You're free to hold up both form and name.
もう一度描いてあなたの思うように青空みたいな画用紙広げて待ってる
Draw it once more, just as you imagine, on a drawing paper like the blue sky, waiting wide open.
夢より夢みたいな未来を進め
Advance toward a future even more dreamlike than dreams!
なんにもしないのはなにもできないからカラッポで助け
Doing nothing means doing nothing, so being empty and...
助けてと言えない
Even when we can't say "help me,"
みんなそれぞれ大変なんだし
everyone has their own hardships, but...
でも笑顔になれる世界がすぐそばにあるじゃん！
A world where we can smile is right beside us!
気づいてワンクリック
Notice it with one click,
扉は開く
and the door will open.
優しい顔してる
With a gentle expression,
幸せばかりじゃない
it's not just about happiness.
険しい道にも
Even on rugged paths,
可愛い花が咲いている
cute flowers are blooming.
何度でも描いて
Draw it as many times as you like,
自惚れちゃう自画像
a self-portrait you can fall in love with.
青空みたいな画用紙広げて待ってる
Like a blank sheet of paper looking at the blue sky,
広げて待ってる
waiting with open arms.
夢より夢みたいな未来で会いたい
I want to meet you in a future more dreamy than a dream.
かなしみはよろこびに混ぜ合わせて
Blend sadness into joy,
blend sadness into joy.
くるしみはしあわせに解け合いたい
and dissolve suffering into happiness,
好きな色に生まれ変わるために
so we can be reborn in our favorite colors.
どこにもないものは誰もまだ知らないだけ
What doesn't exist anywhere is just something no one knows yet.
形も名前も自由に掲げいんだ
Freely raise its shape and name!
もう一度描いて
Draw it once more,
あなたの好きなように
just the way you like.
青空みたいな画用紙広げて待ってる
Like a blank sheet of paper looking at the blue sky,
広げて待ってる
waiting with open arms.
夢より夢みたいな未来を進め
Let's move forward into a future more dreamy than a dream!
進め
Move forward!